avtronaero.com 2018-10-17

# Privacy Policy - Avtron Aerospace

### Privacy

Effective January 6, 2010, Avtron Aerospace respects and protects the privacy of our clients and web site visitors. This Privacy Policy explains how visitors’ “and clients’ ” personal information is collected and used. This Privacy Policy applies to the Avtron Aerospace web site and our products and services. Visitors and clients can update their personal information by visiting one of our personal preference pages or by emailing [sales@avtronaero.com](mailto:sales@avtronaero.com).

**Information Collection and Usage**

Avtron collects information at several different points on our web site in order to better serve client and visitor needs. Avtron is the sole owner of the information collected on this site. Under no circumstances will Avtron sell, share or rent this information in any manner to any unaffiliated third parties.

Avtron’s web site offers opportunities for visitors to register for promotional and informational mailings, online resources, and for assistance in evaluating our products and services. These registration forms enable users to opt-in to Avtron’s mailing lists and require users to give contact information (such as name and email address). We use this contact information to send the requested information about our company, products and services. Notice is given at the point of collection to enable users to choose whether or not they consent to the usage terms. Those who have signed up and subsequently wish to withdraw their participation may opt out of receiving future mailings at any time (see the opt-out section below).

All financial and billing information we collect is used solely to check credit qualifications of prospective clients and to invoice our clients for the purchase of Avtron products and services.

**Opt out and Update of Information**

If an individual no longer wishes to subscribe to Avtron newsletters and promotional communications, he or she can easily opt out of receiving them by following instructions included in each newsletter or communication. If personally identifiable information changes, or if an email recipient no longer desires to receive specific mailings, he or she may correct, update or delete all information or specific details by sending an email to [sales@avtronaero.com](mailto:sales@avtronaero.com).

**Children’s Online Privacy Protection Act (“COPPA”)**

Avtron will not knowingly accept any information from children under the age of 13. For any children under the age of 13, a parent or guardian will need to contact Avtron to provide consent for any portion of the site that gathers personal information. We require our clients to comply with COPPA with respect to their use of Avtron products

**Security and Privacy**

Avtron takes every precaution to protect the confidentiality and security of the personal information of web site visitors and clients by using industry-standard security safeguards, such as firewalls, coupled with carefully developed security procedures. These measures are designed to protect visitor and client information from loss, misuse or unauthorized alteration.

Avtron’s employees and its sub-contractors are required to safeguard client and web-site visitor information. Using physical, electronic and procedural safeguards, we restrict access to such personal information to only those employees with a “need-to-know” for business purposes.

**Automatic Collection of Anonymous Data**

Following standard industry practice, Avtron may use pixel tags and other methods to gather information about the emails it sends to registered web site users and recipients of emails sent by the company’s registered users to others. Pixel tags are tiny graphic files that are included in HTML-encoded email messages. When such a message is opened in an HTML-capable email program, the recipient’s computer will access Avtron’s servers to retrieve the pixel tag file, allowing Avtron to record and store information such as email address, date and time the recipient viewed the email message, if the recipient’s email program is capable of receiving HTML, and other logging information. Avtron uses this information to optimize delivery of future messages to specific recipients and to provide information to registered users with respect to emails they send through the Avtron system.

Avtron maintains log files tracking IP addresses to analyze trends, help diagnose problems with our servers, and to monitor traffic/usage in order to provide better service to our clients and web site visitors.

Avtron uses cookies to deliver content specific to Web-site visitors’ interests and to improve the convenience and efficiency of our clients’ experience when using our products and services. A cookie is a piece of data stored on the user’s hard drive tied to statistical information about the user. Usage of a cookie is in no way linked to any personally identifiable information in Avtron products and email messages. Visitors can always choose to not accept cookies, but in doing so they may not be able to use some of the Avtron products and services. These cookies are used to track visitor behavior, and Avtron has no access to or control over these cookies. This Privacy Policy covers the use of cookies by Avtron only and does not cover the use of cookies by any third parties.

**Sensitive Information**

“Sensitive information” is a subcategory of personal information. Sensitive information is defined as personal information specifying medical or health conditions, racial or ethnic origin, political opinions, religious or philosophical beliefs, trade union membership, or the sex life of the individual. Sensitive information also includes personal information received from a third party where the third party treats and identifies it as sensitive.

**Disclosure**

Transfers of information permitted under this notice, either to third parties or within Avtron, include the transfer of data from one jurisdiction to another, such as transfers to and from the United States of America. Avtron will take reasonable precautions to protect personal information in its possession from loss, misuse and unauthorized access, disclosure, alteration and destruction.

**Dispute Resolution**

If an individual feels this company is not abiding by its posted privacy policy he or she should contact [sales@avtronaero.com](mailto:sales@avtronaero.com).

**Disclosures and Transfers**

Avtron does not disclose personal information to third parties, except when one or more of the following conditions is true:

(i) We have the individual’s permission to make the disclosure;  
(ii) The disclosure is permitted by law or mandatory professional standards;  
(iii) The disclosure is reasonably related to the sale or other disposition of all or part of our business or assets;  
(iv) The personal information to be disclosed is publicly available;  
(v) The party to whom the disclosure is made controls, is controlled by, or is under common control with Avtron;  
(vi) The disclosure is reasonably necessary for the establishment or maintenance of legal claims; or  
(vii) The disclosure is to persons or entities for which we are providing or contracting services, provided the disclosure is consistent with the purpose for which the personal information was obtained.

It is possible that as we continue to develop our business, Avtron may be acquired. In such a transaction, client information may be transferred to the acquiring entity. If, as a result of the business transition, the users’ personally identifiable information will be used in a manner materially different from that stated at the time of collection, they will be given a choice consistent with our notification-of-changes section.

**Links to other Web sites**

Avtron’s web site, or messages created by Avtron, may contain links to other web sites. Avtron is not responsible for the privacy practices or the content of such other web sites. Third parties may independently collect information about web site visitors when visitors view ads or other communications from third parties’ sites. If visitors do not want those companies to collect information about them, they should contact these companies directly.

**Changes to this Policy**

Avtron will notify its subscribers via email if any changes are made to our Privacy Policy. If at any point we decide to use personally identifiable information in a manner different from that stated at the time it was collected, we will notify impacted subscribers via email. Subscribers will have a choice as to whether or not we use their information in this different manner.

**Contact Us**

If you have questions or concerns regarding this Policy, you should first contact us at the contact address listed below or via email at [sales@avtronaero.com](mailto:sales@avtronaero.com).

**Avtron Aerospace**  
**Attn: Privacy Policy**  
**7900 E. Pleasant Valley Road**  
**Cleveland, OH 44131**  
**Phone: 216-750-5152**
